Krishnan Shankar



krishnans2006@gmail.com



5712763427



linkedin.com/in/krishnan-shankar



https://github.com/KrishnanS2006

Summary

I am a High School Sophomore specializing in Full-Stack Web Development. I mainly use Python, integrated with Flask, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Firebase, and/or SQL, to create fully-functioning web applications. I am also skilled in advanced Pygame, and I have built multiple Discord Bots using Discord.py. In addition to Python, I am also skilled in Java and can program classes and Java Swing GUIs. Finally, I have experience using Linux (Ubuntu, Arch Linux, and Debian on a Raspberry Pi), Git and GitHub, and deploying using Heroku or AWS Elastic Beanstalk.

Experience



Hobby Projects

High School

Aug 2020 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

Webitor is a site builder, tester, and hosting platform whose goal is to assist people in making a website, without the stress of writing a lot of code. Webitor includes an interactive code editor and live preview, along with auto-generated code snippets that use Bootstrap, a popular web framework. It also lets you host your site on a subdomain!

Coded Using: Python Flask, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Uses: Heroku Deployment

YouTube Party is a platform where you and your friends can watch a YouTube video together, and chat about it the entire time! With support for team rooms and invites, YouTube Party allows you and your friends to watch a YouTube video and chat with your friends real-time while watching it!

Coded Using: Python Flask, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Firebase

Uses: SocketIO, Repl.it Hosting

In Space Warfare: Jovian Conflict, a real-time strategy game, you can experience space warfare as close to how it would theoretically play out in real life. Command a fleet of warships and battle your friends in unique planetary systems. The game design and mechanics are based on actual theorizations and research about space warfare in real life.

Coded Using: C#, Unity

PollCOVID is a website that lets you rate and view ratings for various stores and businesses in your area. Using Google Maps Autocomplete, you can select a location and view its ratings for Crowd, Social Distancing, and Masks. You can also submit your own ratings to help others stay safe during the pandemic.

Coded Using: Python Flask, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL

Uses: Google Places API, Glitch

TimeXtension is a set of browser extensions designed to help you manage your online browsing time! It records your current tab every minute, determines whether the site is productive using a complex algorithm, and then displays your productivity in a simple Pie Chart. It even syncs through your browser account on all your devices!

Coded Using: JavaScript, Chart.js

View the rest of my projects at https://krishnan.web.app/.

Computer Programmer

TJUAV

Feb 2021 - Present (11 months +)

TJUAV is TJ High School's Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) Team. We participate in the annual AUVSI SUAS competition, where we compete with an Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) against colleges from around the world. In 2019, TJUAV placed 23rd overall out of over 75 college teams (auvsi-suas.org for more information). Working on the airframe, designing electrical systems, engineering a ground vehicle, developing an autopilot system, transmitting data with an aircraft, and autonomously classifying images are common tasks.

Technical Lead

HackAlphaX

Dec 2020 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

As the Technical Lead of HackAlphaX, I am responsible for updating and maintaining the official site (hackalphax.co) and all other technology used to help ensure NextStep Hacks runs smoothly.

Operations Lead

HackAlphaX

Dec 2020 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

As the Operations Lead of HackAlphaX, I handle the operations before, during, and after the hackathon, by making sure everything runs smoothly. I am also the Point-of-Contact of the HackAlphaX Executive Team during the Hackathon, for any rules clarifications or questions.

System Administrator

Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology

Jun 2021 - Present (7 months +)

The Student Systems Administrators are a group of students who maintain computer equipment and networked services in TJ's Computer Systems Lab (CSL). We run services which power the entire school's operations, including TJ Email accounts and a student-run and developed project known as the TJ Intranet, used daily by students and staff, which manages the Eighth Period student activity program. Sysadmins manage over 30 physical servers and 60 student workstations, all powered by GNU/Linux and open source software.

Computer Programmer

Project Caelus

Oct 2021 - Present (3 months +)

I help program various parts of Project Caelus, including crucial components like the Launch Box, Ground Station, and Flight Software. The mission at Project Caelus is to design, build, test, and launch a bipropellant liquid-fueled rocket to the edge of space, making history as the first high-school group to take a liquid-fuel rocket to space.



Electronic Engineer

Project Caelus

Oct 2021 - Present (3 months +)

I help design electronic circuits and PCBs for Project Caelus, such as the launch box and pressure control valves. I also help wire electronic components to one another, and to the Ground Station to be handled by code.



Corporate Sponsorship Coordinator

HackTJ

Jun 2021 - Present (7 months +)

HackTJ brings together 500 of the brightest students on the East Coast to TJ's own student hackathon. Here, high school students learn how to build their own apps and websites in just 24 hours! As part of the HackTJ Team, I am responsible for updating and maintaining the official website of HackTJ (hacktj.org), along with judging projects and coordinating with sponsors.

Labs Intern at CodeDay

CodeDay

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

DigiChef is a website to help you find what you would like to cook, and publish your recipes in a simple and effective way! DigiChef's goal is for its users to discover new recipes without the extra filler. The frontend of DigiChef is created using React and Material-UI. The backend uses Django REST Framework and a PostgreSQL Database to provide a JSON API for the frontend to use. Both the frontend and the backend are hosted as a Docker Container using AWS.

Education



Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology

High School Diploma, Computer Science Aug 2020 - Jun 2024

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • HTML • Git • System Administration • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • Firebase • Cloud Firestore • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • AWS Elastic Beanstalk

Honors & Awards



President's Volunteer Service Award (Gold) - Presidential Service Awards

Nov 2021

For volunteering more than 100 hours for HackAlphaX (a recognized nonprofit organization), I was issued the Gold Presidential Volunteer Service Award.

In 2003, the President's Council on Service and Civic Participation founded the President's Volunteer Service Award to recognize the important role of volunteers in America's strength and national identity. This award honors individuals whose service positively impacts communities in every corner of the nation and inspires those around them to take action, too.